hi everybody welcome back to the channel
today we are going to look at these
dairy-free plant-based creams
not let us say really so let's just see
what's what
[Music]
so the in-laws are over from the UK one
of them is dairy free
um in the UK there is an excellent cream
substitute uh I'll put a link below
if you want to use it I mean it's it's
impeccable you can use it in ice cream
actually to some degree it creates
better flavors or better ice cream for
some flavors it's it's that good you
don't have the options over here in
Canada we've got silk which is I think
coconut
based
let's say somewhere
uh ingredients filtered water coconut
oil sunflower oil fava Bean
protein go our gum sunflower less than
and natural flavoring whatever the hell
that is and this again silk
um coconut base again
uh which is water and coconut cream an
oat base which is water gluten-free oat
flour
coconut oil fiberian protein is
basically the same gallon gum this one's
stabilized with gell and gum natural
flavor again what the hell is that I
don't really like using
coconut flavored stuff if I want to make
coconut ice cream I'll make coconut ice
cream
not at all
that's better
so you know if I don't yeah I don't know
the obsession it seems to
I'm convinced that
commercial businesses think that
everyone is
following a plant-based diet once
everything to tastes coconut
you don't
there's no need to either so we're gonna
just try a little bit of each
and see which one
tastes better
now obviously when you make ice cream
the cream and or dairy is quite a strong
flavor and smell so if you end up making
plant-based ice cream with coconut cream
then no matter what you add to it it's
gonna have this coconut undertone and I
remember going to an ice cream place in
Calgary last year
although the ice cream there is
impeccable by and large their
plant-based still all tasted of coconut
and that really disappointed me so
here we go what what's this is the
yeah 10.5 this is a coconut oat based
mix doesn't smell a coconut
very slight Taste of coconut very slight
it's quite creamy mouth feel
lingers quite a bit you can tell it
stabilized
but not too bad 10.5 fat that's a
that's going to be an ice cream recipe
that
is going to be a bit different here we
go
also doesn't smell a coconut
[Music]
oh
tastes weird
that's got a very strange taste to it
it tastes completely artificial
right
I'm gonna go with this one
so we're going to make a plant-based
chocolate Midnight Cookies now I know
it's chocolate again and I apologize I
don't apologize actually it's my
favorite flavor
but I made my mother-in-law this ice
cream
last year
it was one of our retail flavors back in
England
and
chocolate Midnight Cookies is a
Haagen-Dazs history flavor
amazing ice cream they stopped selling
it I don't know why it is a chocolate
ice cream with cookie pieces so it's
like the outside of Oreos and a
chocolate fudge swirl and it had a lot
of it in it so that's what we're going
to create in dairy-free plant-based
vegan whatever you want to call it
that's what we're doing so let's get on
with it right what do we need obviously
we've got this we've got a scales got a
pan got those got a spoon we need some
cocoa powder sugar dextrose cocoa powder
we're gonna go with Ghirardelli there
you go
dextrose yes
normal sugar
it's because I bought myself some new
slippers do you want to see
slippers
not affiliated
I'm an idiot
right here we go so
I've calculated this on
ice cream calculator plant-based ice
creams are difficult on ice cream
calculators because
the ingredients are different everywhere
for whatever it is that you're buying so
you have to kind of look at it a bit
more loosely
obviously fat is still fat regardless of
where it comes from
the sugar is sugar the dextrose is just
you know another type of sugar and the
cocoa powder is fine what you're going
to struggle with is your milk solids
non-fat part of an ice cream recipe and
that is obviously because it's
plant-based
so you have to kind of
look at the solids area for vegan
recipes
solids are can be quite difficult to
to get
you've got things like inulin which I
can't use doesn't agree with me
um a lot of people can't eat it um some
most people I think a lot of people I
think most people can
wait for the dishwasher
maybe it'll stop in a minute
um I think most people can stomach
inulin but if you have too much You're
Gonna Know It
so I just don't use it I'd rather not so
solids has to come from somewhere and
this is why things like oat flour
tapioca starch that kind of thing come
into play
we're quite lucky here with chocolate
based
recipes because the cocoa powder is
obviously a form of solids so let's just
measure it all out and get it on hob
first things first what do we need
grams
we are going to need 700 grams of our
dairy free half and half
700 grams it's kind of I can
off-white color
like a gray
brownie white color kind of reminds me
of PVA glue actually
700 grams 701 grams
put that aside
and now
we need
this part of dextrose in
which is 20 grams
rip
probably a tiny bit more yep
yep
20 grams of extras
it would be nice to get a tripod so I
don't have to keep bending over getting
old back out
190 grams of sugar
there we go always make
always makes me laugh when you go online
and people say healthy ice cream low fat
yeah it's loadable sugar
it's one or the other if it's low sugar
and low fat
you got a problem
and 65 grams of cocoa powder
65 G's
see where we get
I actually really like the Ghirardelli
cocoa powder
let's um it's got a really nice kind of
milk chocolatey taste to it
back in the UK
I used to use calabo cocoa powder which
is excellent I can't get it over here
foreign
so we're not putting stabilizers per se
in this right this second I want to get
the cocoa powder Incorporated first if
you really wanted to put it in before
you absolutely could just add it to your
sugar
but they're stabilizers already in this
milk
what did I say it was gallon gum
I think I said it was gallon gum
so let's just see what the viscosity is
like and that's really a great
indication for how stabilized your ice
cream is going to be
if the viscosity is about right the
chances are your ice cream
ice cream result will be about right
if your ice cream is very very thin
too much water too much free water
anyway
let's get this mixed up okay
we're at about 55 degrees we don't need
to go mad with this we're just trying to
dissolve the ingredients I do want to I
did
I didn't want to do this cold process
because I wanted to try and reactivate
the stabilizer in
cream
viscosity looks quite good so I'm not
going to add any other stabilizers just
gonna try it see what see what happens
let's get it in a bowl
it's got a nice dark color but not too
dark
texture consistency so far looks okay
all right let's
pop this in a fridge
and then I'll do some cleanup
and we'll make the fudge swirl
all the ingredients for this stuff is
below by the way in the description so
50 grams of sugar 50 grams of
chocolate at 80 cocoa powder 10 grams 50
grams of Plum based milk or cream 15
grams of corn syrup golden syrup 15
grams of coconut oil 3 grams of vanilla
extractio
all right let's get everything ready
[Music]
I'm sorry and vanilla We'll add that
after right let's get some heat
tiny whisk a little bit different with
this stuff what you you actually want to
boil this
you'll want to get it hot you'll want
the the fats to emulsify with the cocoa
powder you want the chocolate to melt
but it's about the sugars
it's about turning those
invert sugars
into a more stable mix
just don't go too mad until you're
you know
boiling it with an injury into its life
just get it up to that stage
there we go with all all the chocolate
has melted all the sugars dissolved I
can just see some bubbles now coming up
from the bottom which means we're
we're nearly there and that's it we're
going to turn the heat off take it off
and then just keep stirring it
for a couple of minutes
and then we can pour it off into a
container
that's it and what you get is a really
nice
very rich chocolate fudge sauce
doesn't matter whether it's
Dairy plant-based
it tastes just as good either way
takes two minutes to make
and you can do it ahead of time
and store it in the fridge
so we're going to put the lid on
and just
leave it
this will last out on the top for days
I've had it last well over a week before
um it
kind of solidifies but kind of doesn't
so when you're ready to use it Stir It
Up you can put it in the microwave for
five seconds just to loosen it up and
then we'll add it into our ice cream but
for now let's pop it to the side until
the ice cream is completely chilled
mix has been in the fridge overnight
we're gonna
consistency looks good
considering this new stabilizer in there
let's put it in the machine's churn
let's get our Oreo pieces prepped and
ready we've got our fudge ready to go
this is going to take about 15 minutes
foreign
[Music]
for the ice cream to churn and then
we'll load it all the tubs
all right we've got the cookies in there
now we're going to leave some because in
the original
chocolate Midnight Cookies
they had some really big pieces and we
don't want
all of the cookie to be decimated by the
machine so we're going to leave some to
fold in at the end
okay we're gonna we've turned the
chiller part of our machine off we're
going to give this just a minute to
churn we're going to take this out just
a minute or so earlier than normal
because I want to make sure that it's
soft enough to fold the cookies in and
the fudge all together if you take it
out at the normal kind of texture so you
know a good soft serve consistency
sometimes you don't get the ability to
fold all your other ingredients in
properly
ah
let's get another container
and let's get loading
so I put in one scoop one spoonful we're
gonna put in a few pieces of the Oreo
we're gonna put in a big swirl of our
fudge
like that
whip
and then you can just tap it if you want
to stir it in
can we're gonna just not stir it we're
gonna fold it like so
and then we'll do it again and that is
that
we're gonna put the lid on
put that in the freezer
now it's going to be overnight
it's been days since I filmed this it's
been in the freezer it's you know hard
plant-based stuff try not to get too mad
but sugars
I think a lot of you want lower sugar
recipes but something to know is the
lower the sugar the harder the ice cream
and the freezer
you can kind of do something about that
with dextrose glucose you know invert
sugar you can make it slightly softer
but you do run the risk of changing the
balance of the recipe
if you don't know what you're doing so
with that in mind sometimes it's easy
just to leave it as it is and then give
it a couple of minutes now whilst we
wait for that to warm up
look what turned up
my bowl
this is one of the things that survived
the fire with all our stuff in
so I'm quite excited to get some of this
scooped up
and see what it tastes like
[Music]
scooped quite nicely didn't have to wait
long only a minute or so
being plant-based you've got to be
careful with ingredients because the ice
cream calculators don't really work for
plant-based stuff so you kind of gotta
wing it a little bit you've got to
understand the effects of the solids how
to calculate solids in ingredients that
the calculators don't like to use
you've got to know about the sugars
you've got to know about your protein
content all this kind of stuff
and that's how you can get a really
really good plant-based ice cream
most people just use coconut
I I hate tasting coconut that's not in a
coconut ice cream you know if you've got
a chocolate ice cream you don't always
want it to taste the coconut so let's
see what this tastes like
[Music]
fudgy it's rich
it's sweet enough
it's got that fudge Ripple that fudge
sauce going through it
soft-ish bite from the cookies
this is good
now Haagen-Dazs did the chocolate
Midnight Cookies or
I had like three or four names I did a
whole video on it
I'll put a link in the description below
might even stick it up here it was one
of their better ice creams and
as we've got visitors at the moment and
one of them doesn't eat dairy
it's an excuse to make a really good ice
cream that avoids all the dairy
completely plant-based ingredients nice
and easy
so if you want to make
plant-based chocolate Midnight Cookies
by Haagen-Dazs this is the video for you
and thank you very much for watching if
you've made it this far don't forget to
like And subscribe and I'll see you next
week
[Music]
foreign